[Music]
hello and welcome to this the latest
episode or award-winning series podcast
Series MVP the Master's Voice podcast
I'm your host and friend ban Arava
founder editor of mediab brief. comom
and with me on this video and audio
podcast today is a remarkable respected
professional in fact she's a young
veteran please join me as I
welcome she Kapur head of marketing
corporate Communications and CSR at ICI
Lombard one of India's most respected
and preferred companies in the entire
Insurance space Shea welcome to the show
and thank you so very much for your time
you're doing this on uh like end of the
day on a Friday so thank you very much
and welcome no thank you the pleasure is
mine uh thank you Pavan for having me
and I look forward to an interesting
delightful conversation indeed wonderful
just as I do thank you you and thanks
also to simron Gil of adfactors PR and
Rema Mani of your copom team you know
you've got some excellent coms teams
working for you so uh they made this
interaction possible right so sheina
before we begin our conversation please
let me do you the courtesy of telling
our viewers and listeners a little about
you so by your leave here
goes my distinguished guest from this
episode of MBP the master voice podcast
is sha Kapoor head of marketing
corporate Communications and CSI at
ICICI Lombard Shea joined ICI Lombard in
January 2022 from ELO Financial Services
Ido wealth management and after 11 years
at the Times of India so that's amazing
sha has played a significant role in
maintaining the ICI Lombard stature in
the comms marketing and CSR space
positioning the brand as a prominent
player in the industry all these it's
always remained a giant and continues to
shine sheena's an active LinkedIn user
with the quy style seen in her posts
through which she shares her personal
thoughts and content related to ICICI
Lombard and Shea was recently honored
with the digital marketing leader 2023
award uh Shea is an MBA in marketing has
a brand marketing course from ISD Shea
also has a defense background which we
know uh is always a great uh growth area
for truly wonderful professionals across
the spectrum of industry and Enterprise
right and so Shea like of the defense
background and a deep attachment to Pune
and she frequently travels between
Mumbai and Pune or wherever else she is
during the weekend so that in very brief
is about Shina kapor my distinguished
guest on this episode of M mediab
[Music]
bre.com Sheena first please share very
briefly about IC Lombard's product
portfolio and what it does in the CSR
space you know just the top lines of
both we'll discuss CSR at some length
later I mean just give me the
introduction to isia Lombard yeah right
so icsl Lombard you know and I'm very
privileged and fortunate to be working
with them we are um the number one
private General insurer in the country
from a product portfolio General
Insurance in simple layman terms as
non-life which predominantly includes
health insurance your motor insurance
which includes car two wheelers
four-wheelers um the entire spread and
travel insurance uh so for retail guys
are wanting to travel overseas or even
domestic uh we have insurance for the
commercial lines uh which takes care of
uh you know servicing the needs for
smmes and corporates which includes
products like Group Health um you know
fire liability Marine um to cater to the
business needs of the customers from a
CSR um perspective just very broadly uh
we have been running uh multiple
Flagship programs um we work closely
also with the icsf foundation the parent
uh we have won numerous awards for our
CSR initiatives and I think um very you
know distinctly it is it highlights the
heart of the brand of icsl Lombard uh
the flagship programs include um the
likes of right to safety which is about
a helmet distribution and links very
closely with synergies with our motor
insurance um we work very closely again
on the sanitation uh side with nanali
which is you know installing water
purifiers solar panel uh installations
uh working with the rural centers in
equipping um them with some medical
equipment and healthc Care Facilities um
and we also have uh a very ambitious and
a very dear toheart uh one one of the
largest employee volunteering
initiatives that we run called Caring
Hands wonderful you know I can see the
passion for CSR also I'm sure you do
everything with equal passion uh you
have asked and a big wide broad role but
uh you know I think you answered quite a
bit of one of my future questions that's
going to be coming up on CSR but I'm
sure you'll be sharing a lot more
insights later but thank you very much
for that lovely quick brief walk through
and now do you want to walk us through
very quickly through your educational
and professional Journey before you
joined IC Lombard I mean I know you've
got uh even an ISB marketing degree but
just walk us through your educational
and professional Journey before you
joined I
no sure um I mean starting from the
education like you mentioned uh again uh
I feel very fortunate to have been born
to a forgy household uh you know Dad's
now retired um but that was really uh
gives me a lot of uh foundational um you
know the formative years in terms of the
skills which have later helped me in the
long run um and looking back you know
that has been a tremendous uh learning
and support for me uh most of my my grad
postgrad was done in Pune because that's
where my folks and dad retired and
settled um done my um graduation and
postgrad from symbis sibm MBA I later
did the brand marketing course from ISB
um most of my working life has actually
been in um Ami Mumbai and um started my
career uh with a management consulting
firm so straight out of college um and I
I think I've been again blessed to have
been a straight grade a student so I was
a merit topper in you know C and the
first student to get placed on campus um
with management consulting I think it
was also you know it was great to get
that exposure working with the SE Suite
uh in boardrooms and you know listening
to the kind of organizational challenges
that CEOs really grapple with uh post
which like you mentioned yes a long part
of my career has been with the times of
India group so I when I started uh Times
of India I joined them in their um
Financial Services Division called times
of money with a flagship uh brand called
remit to India um and we were India's
first online pioneering remittance
solution and I'm talking way back you
know 2003 2004 when internet itself was
very nent so to get nris to send money
back home uh into India using internet
um you know services from a non-banking
entity that to because we were part of a
Media Group um so that was the times of
money stint post which um I moved uh
internally with times and that was
actually the closest that I've gotten to
being an entrepreneur that was on the
real estate side so it was a real estate
division of uh ARA property where we
were actually seven of us co-founding
members who built and scaled that brand
um and we got into real estate uh
marketing and and later into the
development and then I uh moved again
internally with Times of India group um
I think um you know uh they were very
kind enough every time I really wanted
to look at a different role or an
opportunity uh the group was kind enough
to not want to let me go and uh retain
and you know give me a further Challenge
and that's how I moved internally and I
was heading Innovations for Times of
India or pan India and that's where I
moved to the media side of
[Music]
things and what influenced your decision
to join IC Lombard it's a great brand of
course highly respected but what else in
the company and its profile Drew you uh
into IC so I've been with the financial
services like after my time stint I was
with the adal wise Group which again you
know uh again a very fabulous tint
fabulous group um and the reason why I
decided to move uh to ISS a Lombard was
a uh it gave me an opportunity to work
with a market leader um my earlier stint
with adal wise group I was heading
corporate mark marketing for the group
at large and while the canvas was really
big and the learnings were great um icsl
Lombard allowed me uh the opportunity to
get deeper into a business to understand
you know when you're are part of a
business unit um rather than looking at
the group at large the kind of learnings
and the kind of deeper insights that you
get uh working closely with the business
stakeholders so that was one big uh part
of it um I had huge respect and I
continue to have huge respect um for our
MDM CEO U Mr bhav Das Gupta it's another
story that he's on his way out as we
speak um but uh for me it was about bav
sanjie the other leadership um and it
spoke volumes about the kind of uh
Talent um you know and the culture that
they had built here um which which was a
great uh move for me and over and above
because you know I've I've headed
marketing now in in various stints this
role allowed owed me to also head and
work closely in the CSR space so that's
what drew me you know to icsa longard
wonderful from corporate marketing at
adal WISE Financial Services to
marketing and PR for adal wise wealth
management and a solid 11 years at the
Times of India group what do you feel
have been the learnings and Leadership
strengths in brief very brief whatever
that you might might want to share uh
that you've carried with yourself across
your entire past journey to icic Bard
just three or four you know very
important things that you always hold
most important in all that you do no I I
think um and it's it's got very little
to do with the kind of industry or the
role that you may be involved in it's
got to do a lot more about how you are
as a professional um and as a leader um
I truly believe that anybody can be a
boss by virtue of the designation they
hold they very few who are able to
become and walk the talk as a leader uh
so for me you know the learnings um and
that have helped me grow in my career um
and um you know and and I keep sharing
this with my team you know across um one
has been you know uh when I and and this
was very early on in my career um where
I was literally in my early 20s and um
uh after literally about say two you
know 2 and a half years workex I stopped
waiting for a to Doo list from my boss
you know um you know and I I was the one
who was hungry for growth for learning I
was always very curious to know what was
the CEO discussing you know say with the
promoters or with the shareholders or
with the investors I was always very
curious to learn what were the kind of
strategic discussions that were
happening and I was because I was very
eager to learn and grow and hungry to
work I think I used to go
proactively um you know to to the
leaders and say Hey you know give me
more work because I want to do more work
I want to learn and two I used to come
up with proactive ideas so literally you
know I think ever since the age of you
know say 23 24 um a lot of my work has
been self initiated I'm a selfstarter
and I take ownership and that has been I
think one of the biggest differentiators
uh because uh you know it it brings
about the passion and you get reward
on the flip side you get rewarded with
more work so you get more
stretched
buted with more work and get stressed
and what a beautiful word cloud before I
forget you know because I haven't been
taking notes as you've been talking but
it has all struck home and I've
corrected some gold dust for my uh
viewers and listeners and I want to talk
about these wonderful words one is your
continuous uh you know desire and drive
to keep learning being proactive self
initiating ideas and thoughts and you
know must have been what would have told
the times uh folks that okay from Real
Estate to this to that and to the other
give her what she wants to do and you
must have shown in all that's why you
sort of moved from so many aspects of uh
you know selling with Times of India
group in India and how beautifully well
you perform there and look at where you
are today so wonderful superb right uh
so more than 20 years of work X Shea and
about a year and a half or so at ICC
Lombard behind you from that perspective
mix what is your vision as the marketing
in corporate Communications and CSR head
uh for these functions for icic Lombard
in the coming years see a a Forward
Thinking uh learning hungry person who's
smart who's got so much of wonderful
experience to back her you know I'm sure
you will be able to give us some very
interesting Insight especially
considering the evolving landscape of
the insurance industry so your vision
how you perceive uh this wonderful
company that you are with ICS Lombard uh
moving ahead in the coming years no I
think at a very Global macro uh level uh
it's about increasing the insurance
penetration in the country and helping
build India as a resilient Nation uh
because we are the torchbearers for the
industry given our scale and size and
given our you know over 21 Years of
Legacy and the backing of the entire
icsa group uh for me as a marketer if
I'm able to bridge that Gap um and make
our products more accessible make the
brand a lot more authentic empathetic
relatable uh for across the board you
know and um the way I see it is our
brand and we are specially suited and
placed to literally cater to you know a
farmer or a kissan with his or her crop
insurance cattle Insurance you know he's
probably running a taba in some ga and
on this end of the spectrum you know we
are catering to insurers for you know
the the U Uhn who are sitting in their
Beamers or MKS um you know from a very
small udipi restaurant guy you know or
an garment manufacturer to very large
mnc's and corporations you know um and
that's the world that we straddle so as
a marketer my job is and and you know
that's what I hope for that ICS a
Lombard any which ways you know I I
think given the scale that that we enjoy
uh the leadership stance that we enjoy
it makes um that that much job easier
but that much harder as well to maintain
the leadership position and also set new
benchmarks um and I have for the last
year and a half and even in future uh
very clear uh for me that the
communication has to be differentiated
has to be original um you know has to be
relatable so I'm trying to find a lot of
wide spaces so in a lot of the campaign
and communication strategies that we've
done um there's been a lot of fresh
thinking fresh perspective um I keep
pushing the agencies and the team and
now with the whole disruption with AI
and generative AI we're already working
very um closely with the ecosystem and
training our team members on learning AI
tools um so the entire mix uh from media
planning as well you know moving the
needle towards more digital uh towards
more Tech um to implementing mtech
platforms um you know so that you're
able to reach the communication that you
want to the customer that you want to in
the manner that he or she wants to
receive it wonderful wonderful white
spaces new ways of communication New
Attitudes and styles and outreaches I
mean look at what your entire reach your
stature is actually covering the
footprint of it from across India to the
back off Beyond in Bat yes is IC L
leading the way that's truly
[Music]
wonderful so sheina you're charged with
marketing both the customer and partner
offerings from IC Lombard which lead to
revenue and business growth that's one
and two uh talking to the world doing
the CSR initiatives that ICA Lombard is
emotionally invested in so one is the
raising business and helping it grow and
the second is CSR what gives you greater
pleasure and how do you approach
marketing and awareness for both groups
of your TGs for business and brand
marketing and promoting your CSR
initiatives you know take time take each
part in some detail so younger marketers
and aspiring professionals plus the
older ones alike can get some good
insights tell us about what gives you
greater pleasure and why and your mcom
strategy for the different TGs the media
mix please take it away that's a very
interesting and a tough question to
answer
but I enjoy aspects of both uh because
when you talk about the business side of
it um and the marketing there is
research there's datadriven insights uh
that we called there are stories
consumer stories um you know that you um
highlight and there's the whole Art of
Storytelling which I love U there's the
entire brand building uh aspect and the
entire creative Machinery about uh and
the Joy from working on you know some
fabulous campaigns some Innovative work
that's really uh pushing the envelope or
raising the bar you know uh not just for
me but you know for the industry for the
organization um so you know that
obviously gives me a lot of Joy um
personally at at a very heart uh level
um the entire CSR work that we're doing
you know to be able to give back to
society in whatever little but meaning
meaningful ways and to be able to play
you know some sort of a role in that
Machinery that you are somewhere you
know playing a small role in uh helping
somebody's life get better impacting
lives you know through our various
programs is is extremely
heartwarming you know so one is you know
the artistic the creative uh side which
I really love and enjoy and there are
certain campaigns which are very close
to my heart but if you ask me
emotionally you know what touches is my
heart a lot more is you know obviously
the heart of it you know which is on the
CSR and of course being the business and
finance professional also that you the
kind of experience that you have for so
many years is also amazing and that
would come and you would bring it
beautifully into play when you're
looking at building the business side of
things the comms and the initiatives
that actually help the business so I
think it's beautiful you probably
working from that sweet spot between
head and
heart the business absolutely absolutely
head and heart and in in a lot of places
Soul as well oh
yeah you are a poet at heart really
wonderful it's so nice the fun of and
I'm not trivializing something as
beautifully Purpose Driven and crucial
and critical as insurance as one of the
things the greatest fun of doing
something good is to do it really well
and here you have you know head heart
and soul and this wonderful and
professional leading at all so super
super what about the media mix you use
Sheena so it's a function of the
campaign it's a function of the
objective of the campaign I think first
and foremost one needs to as a marketer
understand what is the objective what is
the need gap that you're trying to
address what is the business challenge
that you're trying to support um and
then comes the media mix um you know uh
that you decide on a certain campaign um
for instance there are are certain
campaigns that I may run only for the
objective of creating awareness in which
case the media makes I would possibly
look at more ATL or what we call as
above the line which are more mass media
channels just to be able to disseminate
and Outreach that communication to a
larger set of consumers the flip side of
that is the spillover is is huge um
right and and your traction on the
business side is not as sharp Visa V you
know there are certain campaigns on
product Centric uh that we do where you
know the dunda uh that you want to get
from an Roi perspective that's key uh in
which case you know uh the metrics are
are are different and the media mix is
different um you would do a lot more of
performance-based campaigns you would do
a lot more of digital targeting or you
may do um just a small very focused
sharper communication to the Target
segment that you want to really you go
after um so to just give you an example
for instance you know last year uh when
I joined um and I you know because I was
uh discussing and interacting with a lot
of the business stakeholders I realized
that we had this sweet spot and a wide
space open you know uh for us uh
ourselves which was in the insurance
space because nobody was talking about
it we were the first ones in the country
and the only ones to have a digital
Insurance off offering which was
seamless and I said hey that's great and
you know while from a business size the
potential is large the business size for
the business compared to say health and
motor you know was obviously far um
lower in terms of magnitude but the
potential was large and I felt that this
was a beautiful platform to be able to
now create this and tap into this white
space and positioning to be able to
endure the brand to the business owners
and we broke it up into phases the first
phase of the community communication was
all about building Affinity with the TG
so I didn't want to go ahead with saying
hey we have this sesame Insurance I've
got Tu tuck Tu these products this is
the pricing and here log on this website
or download the app you know rather we
wanted to build the brand love and so
wanted to do an entire campaign where
the SM guy was the hero you know and we
did that as the first uh you know
storytelling as the phase um thereafter
we went into the phase pH two and phase
three which was really about building
the business traction so now that you've
done awareness you've built some
Affinity you've built some reach now you
want to be able to talk to the customers
and say hey we have this XYZ product
this is how it can help you and that's
the kind of targeting so it really
depends on the metrics um and the
campaign objectives the business
objectives and the tges absolutely and
also I think another very good service
you gave to the whole Space is that you
built that category not for business
business but also awareness of the need
and the beauty and the power and the
strength of insurance that it could give
to you know the smaller
Enterprises right wonderful so digitally
sold and to smmes and that was your
[Music]
connect now in the past like you
mentioned you know for big Mass
campaigns awareness because nowadays
what is the uh need or objective of a
campaign it more often than not on the
digital space it not only has to inform
or create customer awareness but also
try and potential customer awareness and
also try and get customers and acquire
them you know it has to be done like
virtually overnight all together in one
go with digital campaigns at least so
for the bigger Mass campaigns you all
used mass media for this digitally sort
of driven for smmes wonderful new
initiative new category that you created
what formats of digital did you use did
you use also connected TV mobile what is
your preference for in terms of
deliveries whether Sports and Cricket or
entertainment what works I mean just
just because see you are a senior leader
and whenever all the mixes and
everything else is planned and done
you're right up there in front so some
insights into say all right big Mass
campaign mass media for awareness across
the country but for this digitally
driven and sold offering on the space
what did you use
just you know some insights for sure
sure we've used again a mix of medium
elements um so yes uh the first phase
was print even television um then we
followed it up with radio within digital
uh because we had our asset uh showcase
which was a film uh we used YouTube meta
partnering with mobile uh lead
communication partnering with
associations on ground because that's
where you knew the e e system ofme
owners uh you know reside targeting
communities you know which are
business-led communities on digital um
using connected TV from a messaging
platform for that some mix of affiliate
marketing uh but really it's a mix of
that because you really want to
understand first where is your TG um and
you know what are the channels of
communication that they are consuming
and then you want to be able to Target
and you know package the entire
messaging and uh Target them with that
communication like even on television um
one is of course you know a function of
the kind of pockets that you have how
deep it is and the Quantum of budgets
that you have um but in case and in more
cases uh more often than not uh what
happens is typically that you you have a
limited uh budget you have limited Kitty
uh available with you and therefore the
ROI needs to be that much sharper um in
which case even on on you know
television we targeted only the specific
news channels rather than G GC channels
because a they were a lot more cost
effective you know than the GC channels
um you know uh Sports Association and
all tends to get very uh expensive a b
um you also have to have a very you know
like I said large spillover and you need
to have guardrails about how much you
want to spend where you want to spend
and why you want to spend um otherwise
you know if I'm targeting everybody
universally I've already done that with
you know the print and some part of the
news because I know that as anme he or
she is more likely to be
watching um the news and both you know
mainstream English Hindi Regional
languages uh print you know Regional um
and then again tying it up with the
business journals or Business Media
because that is closer to a business
owner interest wonderful thank you Shea
that was really nice detailed very
insightful response and it should
definitely help all our listeners our
viewers think strategically uh you know
on how they can work effectively and
impactfully and smartly I mean
spillovers and the kinds of media
platforms that one uses and whether
where they are placed in relation to the
line whether it's above or below all of
that fell in
[Music]
place you know sheina only yesterday a
PR person approached me saying we'd like
to do a special feature on how creators
and influencers use their creativity to
showcase the importance of mental health
day I said when did you do anything at
all for mental health and she said uh
we'll do it on the day you know the
calendar day that kind of tactical
approach without any apparent heart or
emotional investment in it it does tend
to put one off so how do you Shea
approach your CSR initiatives I know
that IC Lombard doesn't make a human cry
about what it does on the CSR front
because there is commitment and a
realness about it if I may use that word
coin that word so the annual CSR spend
in FY 23 was what 3 47.3 million and you
had some great initiatives like you
mentioned you know Nang um Caring Hands
and right to safety but tell us a little
more about each initiative and their
positive impact in brief please yeah I
think pav you touched a very insightful
and uh bang on when you spoke about that
as a customer as a consumer you're able
to sniff out where the brand is being
inauthentic where it is being fake and
you know there are a lot of brands that
try and build in uh purposeful marketing
or try and build in you know some sort
of um and it really boils down to really
it being gimmickry uh more than anything
else and that to my mind you know
doesn't move the needle either ways and
you're right that it actually is a put
off and a turnoff you know uh from the
one you know receiving the communication
and as a consumer lens so I've always
believed that you should be able to walk
the talk you should be able to
demonstrate where your commitment lies
um for IC Lombard you know um like I
mentioned we have a slew of Flagship
programs um you know from a annual
budget and of course CSR budgets you
know as is a mandatory uh you know
requirement is a function of 2% of your
uh you know the profit pool but more
than that I think is the intent um the
alignment with the UN STG goals um and
um now more and more in the boardrooms
and across corporates you will find that
there is a lot of synergy being built
with the ESG mandates and sustainability
measures so you know a lot of
organizations are working towards net
zero they're working towards um reducing
the carbon footprint uh working very
strongly within the ecosystem their
operations their businesses their
Channel Partners you know the subsidary
companies or even the supply chain that
they work with to be able to impact the
entire value chain uh from an integrated
lens um coming to the specific CSR
programs uh for us right to safety for
instance um is is a beautiful exercise
and program where uh taking on from we
are a motor insurer now motor insurance
typically would kick in when there is
Road accidents right when there is
damage to the vehicle from a CSR lens
you want to be able to prevent that you
want to be able to avoid that and you
want to be able to work closely with the
traffic police and we do a lot of work
with the traffic police we work a lot
with the NGO kids uh Municipal kids to
be able to distribute helmets and do a
lot of awareness camps uh saying that
hey you must wear a helmet when you're
sitting on a two- wheeler and we
actually have custom designed kids
helmets which normally you don't find in
the retail space so because we order in
bulk uh given the scale of our um you
know impact programs uh we work closely
with the manufacturers to order in bulk
and customize them even for the kids we
go down to the schools we hold ride to
safety rallies where we call a lot of
kids along with the parents uh we um
also uh you know rope in the principle
the administration the staff we rope in
the traffic police as well you know um
and we create this entire awareness uh
initiative and over and above that we
also distribute helmets um and they're
all isi marked and to supplement this we
do a lot of other video based campaigns
you know um you know to try and drive
Road Safety initiatives you know uh
whether it's about wearing the seat belt
for instance um having and adopting uh
um you know responsible and not Reckless
uh driving behavior on roads educating
uh public towards that lovely Shea and
what about nangali yeah nangali is again
one of our Flagship programs uh where
you know like right to safety we already
had access to the schools the Municipal
schools and uh because we're also in
health insurance and most of our
programs are aligned with our lines of
businesses we felt uh that there was a
need and an opportunity to um install
water p iers so that the kids have
access to Safe uh drinking water and
again it aligns with the UN STG goals
and in fact you know we take care so
that we actually check the water levels
and the TDS levels of the water before
installing the water purifier so it's
only if it's above 300 do we install the
water purifier um because you know if
the water's a already portable there's
no need uh but B it also helps us um you
know uh get carbon credits uh um you
know which are aligned with our ESG
mandate um and in the same schools we
are also able to work closely with the
principles of the school and enable them
and help them with conservation of
energy and bringing down their
electricity costs by installing solar
panels so again it's on the
sustainability measure but for the
school therefore we have taken on an
entire ecosystem where the kids you know
get helmets uh when they can come to
school so it's safe they get access to
safe drinking water um and you know the
school saves electricity bills because
now it's zero ised with solar panels
excellent you know this entire thing is
so beautifully linked with and
demonstrates how wonderfully well ICC
Lombard walks the talk on the CSR space
because I mean why put so much of
thought and work into it when you could
just say okay here are the top 10 most
respectible NOS let's just give them the
money that they need to use and look at
every aspect but what you're doing is
actually encouraging people to remain
safe to bring in the habits and to
protect them healthwise also right from
you know the young age and you know
talking about right to safety about
nangali okay and also I think you're
also encouraging reverse mentoring by
young kids of their parents you know in
terms of how the responsible safe
driving uh Etc has to be really uh
adhered to any interesting video
campaign I'm sure all of them must have
been interesting but something close to
your heart that we can play out here and
then from there we'll move on to the
other uh questions yeah sure but I want
to cover one more aspect on our CSR
program which is on Caring Hands which
is um actually the you know out of all
the programs that we run on CSR this
one's really special this um CSA program
actually is is exceptional and very
special because um it actually is one of
the largest employee volunteering
initiatives for any organization on this
one particular singular day we have
close to about 4,000 employees from you
know over 10,000 12,000 employee
ecosystem of ICS Lombard that go out to
you know uh over 50 um uh cities and
over 350 schools where we cover ey
checkup camps for the kids and this is
completely done 100% through employee
volunteering initiatives we just
centrally hold uh you know from the CSR
lens the entire infrastructure and the
Machinery of it it's done completely by
um by the employees and in fact even our
mancom you know our CEOs our CFOs they
go down to the schools and uh lend a
hand um on the ey checkups so that's on
Caring Hands there is also our um CPR uh
video that we had done with Imran uh
hashimi um you know on world hard day um
on the health side so we can play that
as well there's a quirkiness to Imran
Hashmi driving a CPR campaign yes but
that but that's really smart and very
very attention grabbing because the
point is you're doing something good for
society be was very clever clickbait in
the concept itself which is why we chose
Imran
Hashi smart bust the myths about that
you know CPR is the kiss of life and you
know sadly because of media and the
portrayal of that it gets uh subjugated
to being very trivial and frivolous um
you know as a romantic linkage but it's
a life-saving device absolutely let's
watch the
[Music]
videos
hio
K right wrong it's a
myth kiss or
CPR one is about romance and the other
one is about saving a
[Music]
life
CPR is for everyone
parents
[Music]
World CPR save a life so kiss the myth
goodbye IC
Lombard really wonderful very very
interesting and so much of thought and
planning has had gone into it obviously
so truly you close the loop so
beautifully you know it's not just about
uh you know you're an insurance IC I
Lombard and ensuring uh the lives
property Etc of people through the
various services that you provide right
that must definitely make you happy
because you are driving profit through
purpose just by the very nature of your
business that itself is amazing but the
CSR initiatives of ycsc Lombard really
do demonstrate how it works the talk so
for that I say great work and I say
thank you for what you do for society
sha thank you and you had a wonderful
video also a lovely campaign for the SM
campaign actually so uh let's have that
video
sure 20% children in the age group of 5
to 12 years have poor vision or Vision
complications amongst them thousands of
underprivileged children face poor
vision symptoms but do not have access
to Quality Vision checkups
surj could not read what is written on
the word properly Mini's eye would
strain when she read from the textbook
for a long time Amit experienced regular
pain in his eyes pry missed classes due
to frequent headaches what's common in
all their stories lack of diagnosis then
one day something changed for surj
minakshi prti Amit and thousands of
underprivileged children in
India because ICC Lombard launched the
Caring Hands initiative in 2011 to
ensure underprivileged children can look
at their future with a better Vision
with a team of experts and employees as
volunteers Caring Hands has been
providing preventive health care
services and spectacles to those in need
so that thousands of children like surj
can read everything clearly at his
history class minakshi can read her
favorite textbook for a longer duration
amid does not face discomfort in his
eyes and headaches don't stop pre from
topping her math
class here's to looking at a bright
clear
future wonderful campaigns across
marketing across CSR a great campaigns
like these are the result of great
client agency relationships right so
with your extensive experience in the
industry how do you perceive the
Dynamics of client agency relationships
today and how do you believe that they
could be enhanced for Mutual benefit
entire ecosystem of client agency it
works I believe on mutual respect um and
I have seen that a lot of times clients
end up abusing the kind of authority and
the kind of hold uh because you know
this side of the bread is buttered uh
and one is receiving and asking for
business while one is holding the purse
strings on the other end of the spectrum
um but I think it's important to a be
mutually respectful uh towards each
other and understand that they're also
human beings at the end of the day and
not just expect um you know that I need
something to be done last minute and I
need this delivered you know and I'm the
client and you know I'm what that's it
I'm I'm just going to throw my weight
around for that so I I find that very
very disrespectful and I find that
rampant in the industry um b i I feel
that it works also beautifully when
there is exchange of ideas when you see
um agencies as not as vendors you know
but as partners as your extended
marketing team and you pull them in on
briefs you pull them in on the Strategic
stuff the set up you know the goal
setting uh the kind of objectives that
you've set for the brand for the for the
organization the kind of challenges that
you're facing grappling within the
organization or the industry Trends the
more information that you share the more
um fluid the exchange of ideas um um you
know the more fertile the kind of ideas
that will come out of it and the more
creativity uh you know gets uh you know
U encouraged um and I also believe that
at the end of the day it's people's
business so to have that chemistry to
have that bonding to be able to you know
have a few laughs to be able to
brainstorm together rather than making
it very
transactional um I think that um is also
important and key um I think as clients
the other aspect is that one finds you
know lazy thinking and lazy marketers uh
who uh you know who kind of just um
Outsource a lot of the thinking to the
agencies and expect them to do the heavy
lifting um you know so which I again you
know doesn't sit well with me because if
you are the marketer and if you are the
client you better than anybody else
should know what the brand um and what
the organization need is what the
customer insights are sure you can
depend on them for ideation and you know
the creative rendering but if you were
expecting that for everything I'm going
to depend and Outsource the thinking you
know to the agencies I think that's not
right um and um it it's also a function
of good client agency relationships
where you push each other um and that I
I appreciate agencies who come back and
push me who come up with a lot of
proactive ideas a lot of different
differentiated original ideas that's
what I really value U because if you're
going to do run-of-the-mill stuff then
you know that's that's been done to
death you know you want to be able to
always you know um think outside the box
and and think about something which is
differentiated which is ownable and
relevant uh for the brand um and I think
a lot of the creativity and originality
stems from that understanding to be able
to also keep pulse on what the
competition is doing what globally you
know uh if there are some great Brands
and you know work that has happened that
you could get inspired by um that kind
of you know sharing and exchange of
information ideas is key I'm sure that
every PR person and every young marketer
you know they would actually appreciate
this because you given such a balanced
perspective and youve put the marketer
in the center in the space where you're
taking the owners and saying I'm here to
help support inform guide whatever and
also to be challenged and pushed by the
agency so you're the kind of marketer I
guess because I haven't worked with you
at that level who would be open to a
first telling an agency I think I want
this this and this to be done and if the
agency says absolutely right uh but
maybe submit that you need these two
things also I think you would say maybe
if you evaluate it you would be open to
being
open to that totally totally I think
ideas great ideas and suggestions can
come from anywhere you know so and and I
I don't even look at hierarchy based
views I'm I'm quite inclusive like that
because it doesn't matter if you're are
a junior client servicing person or the
head of creative in that room you know
if you have a good suggestion and if you
have a valid input absolutely anything
that helps you know build which is which
is making it better for the brand for
the organization or for the customer any
of these three lenses it's great you
know beautiful well said really gold
dust for the youngsters and uh I you
actually answered my next question which
was you know how do you ensure that the
youngsters in your team don't become a
chorus of yes people when they are asked
to say do you like this idea or don't
you yes because somebody saying said yes
you already answered that so but since
we talking about the youngsters for the
budding marketing professionals sheina
who are tuning into our podcast and many
do that regularly what piece of advice
would you offer them as they navigate
the complexities of the marketing well I
would tell them a you know to stay
hungry and actually stay foolish uh also
um stay curious um you know keep your
eyes and ears open because a lot of
times the dots just connect when even if
you were traveling back you know from
office to to home it's about keeping
your eyes open for you know budding
marketers when you look at Great
campaigns of great you know films or
great ideas try and always in your mind
try and think what could have been the
marketing Insight what could have been
the marketing brief rather than seeing
the creative storytelling and getting
you know um you know uh kind of you know
just the trappings of the glamour look
behind the facade and try and look at
what was the insights underlying
strategy uh that's where the thinking
really comes from the other bit I would
say is be proactive you know be a
selfstarter take that sense of ownership
if you want to take up a project drive
it end to end with a sense of ownership
and accountability um you should be able
to leave literally your signature on the
work that you do because you are proud
of the kind of output uh that you want
to really put forth and um you know that
and that kind of work ethic and
credibility if you're able to build the
rest of the pieces will just fall in
place put put your signature thanks to
the quality of what you do on what you
do the work ethic that's about it
because you know if you were seen as
somebody I you know as a boss you know
for young uh young professionals um if
I'm able to see someone who's Dependable
uh who's curious who's wanting to learn
you know that's half the job done
because you know I'm able to rely on the
person and has a good work ethic I know
that he or she does not need micro
managing does not need micro supervision
I don't need to follow up constantly you
know so that level of responsibility
self- ownership is what uh would hold
them in a great stad in time to come and
I wish all of them you know the
listeners the viewers all the very best
really insightful ginaa absolutely
golden advice I really enjoyed my
conversation with you thanks for the
wonderful insights and considering it
has been a long conversation the
Monumental patience and warmth very
grateful to you for that and I know it's
genuine it comes from within us the kind
of person you are so thank you you know
it's good to and it's been great to
breathe the same virtual a since we've
been doing this virtually with you so
like I said I really enjoyed my chat
with you uh what did you think of your
conversation with me on this episode
like likewise I've really enjoyed this
conversation a lot thank you for having
me I'm I'm grateful for the opportunity
as well and I hope that we are able to
meet face to face and not just virtually
so you know we'd love to host you uh
drop by to a prad Dei office if you're
ever the side of town I would love to do
that that is an offer I will not refuse
so thank you ever so much sheina it's
been wonderful what lovely insights you
are a young veteran but my God you a
you're a young Sage we are and copom and
and and marketing and CSR and the entire
uh you know profiling and uh honestly
putting forth your company's
perspectives and such a massive leading
company of the country as C Lombard I
think you both are fortunate to have
each other thanks also Shea to sim Gill
V factors PR and REM man of your ccom
team for having made this interaction
possible I'm going to come and meet up
with you sometimes yes thank you so much
you know you make me sound like I've
achieved a lot but I think I have miles
to go before before I sleep um and but
yeah thank you so much you've been very
very kind thank you wonderful that was
the head of marketing corporate
Communications and CSR at IC Lombard
Sheena Kapoor my distinguished and very
special guest on this episode of going
to be the Master's Voice podcast I hope
you found the conversation extremely
insightful I certainly did tell you meet
again in the next episode of MP the
master voice podcast this is your host
and friend pan Arava saying take care
stay healthy stay safe and stay insured
with the best
bye-bye